TRI-GUNAWAN.md 3/3/2020

Tri Gunawan

Fullstack & Data Analytics

tri.gunawan@live.com

(+62) 857-4367-5495

About

I'm a fullstack & data analytics developer based in Jakarta, Indonesia. Currently working as expert data analytics for corporate risk & integrity at Asia Pulp & Paper. My primary technology skill set is data engineering on top of Python ecosystem. My secondary programming capabilities are with Javascript, React & Vue to build webs apps. In a past life I worked primarily with business intelligence tools, but now I typically use Python whenever I want to build a webs apps, API & data analytics solution. I love doing side project to expand my software development abilities on frontend, backend, dev-ops and data scientist.

Experiences

Asia Pulp & paper (May 2018 - Current)

Expert, Data Analytics

- Main Projects:
- Reporting & Analytics System for Corporate Risk & Integrity. Year: 2018-2020. Stack: Python, Flask, MySQL, Airflow, Metabase/Power BI
- Due Diligence Services Portal. Year: 2019-2020. Stack: Django, Vue, Postgres
- Case Management System for Investigation. Year: 2019-2020. Stack: Django, Vue, Postgres
- Security Incident Report System. Year: 2019. Stack: Django, Vue, Postgres

Kraftheinz Company (October 2015 - April 2018)

Senior Business Intelligence Analyst

- · Main Projects:
- Analytics Report across Finance, Sales, Distribution and Production Department. Year: 2015-2018.
 Stack: PL SQL, SAP Business Object, Oracle DB, MSSQL, Power BI, SSAS, Tableau
- Demand & Supply Predictive Analytics. Year: 2017-2018. Stack: PL SQL, Oracle DB, JDA, MS Access

Multipolar Technology (January 2013 – September 2015)

Business Intelligence Consultant

- Main Projects:
- Business Intelligence System at Harapan Kita Hospital. Year: 2013. Stack: Arcplan, MSSQL, SSIS
- Sales Reporting System at Takeda Indonesia. Year: 2014. Stack: MSSQL, SSIS, SSAS, SSRS
- SAS Migration at Bank Negara Indonesia. Year: 2015. Stack: SAS EG

TRI-GUNAWAN.md 3/3/2020

- Maintenance Reporting System at Bank Indonesia. Year: 2015. Stack: IBM Cognos, MSSQL
- Vision Analytics for Banking Solutions at Multipolar Technology. Year: 2014-2018. Stack: IBM Cognos, Arcplan, MSSQL, SSIS, SSAS, SSRS

Educations

Satya Wacana Christian University

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

• Grade: 3.52

· Major: Software Engineering

• Achievement: Best Student of Computer Engineering 2012/2013-III

· Activities:

Faculty Student Representative 2008/2009 and 2009/2010

• Faculty Student Executive 2010/2011

• Teaching Assistant: Database & Numerical Computation

Skills

· Programing: Python & JavaScript

• Frontend: HTML, CSS, Vue, React

· Backend: Node.js, Django, Flask

• RDBMS: Postgres, MySQL, MSSQL, Oracle

NoSQL: Mongodb, Redis, Elastics, Cassandra

· Cloud: AWS, Azure, GCP

· ML: Scikit, Tensorflow, Pytorch, Keras

• ETL: Airflow, Luigi, SSIS, Talend

· Big Data: Spark, Hbase, Hive, Sqoop, Strom

• Data Viz: Maplotlib, Bokeh, Tableau, Qlik, PowerBI, Redash, Superset, ELK

• Dev Ops: Linux, Nginx, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, Kubernates, Sentry

Contact

Github: https://github.com/trigunawan89 Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/trigunawan